Why
should I feel
discouraged?
And why should the shadows
come?
And why should my heart
feel lonely
and long
for heaven
and home?
When Jesus
is my portion,
a constant
friend
is he.
his eyes on
the sparrow
and I know that he watches
over me.
Let not your heart
be troubled.
His tender words
I hear
and resting on
his goodness
I lose my doubt
and fear
though by the path
he leadth.
But one step I may see
his eyes on
the sparrow.
And I know that he watches
over me.
I sing because
I'm happy
and I sing
because I am free.
His eye is on
the sparrow.
And I know
I know
I know.
His
eyes on
the sparrow.
And I know
he watches
over me.
Oo,
I know way down in my heart
that he's watching
over you
and me.
Heat up
here.
Heat
up here.
Heat up here.
Heat
up Heat.
Heat.
Amen. Happy Sabbath everyone. Um
hopefully the link for the uh Living
Mana channel aids back up as well as the
Power of the Lamb channel. Um we're
going to go ahead and just uh invite you
again to share this link for uh people
who may have uh got booted off and
are trying to get back on. Please go
ahead and share this link. Let your
people know that the sermon
is about to begin. And um we have a very
special word. Um we have some special
living mana today uh from the word of
God. So I'm going to invite you to uh
please pray with me uh as we seek God's
face. Let's pray. Heavenly Father,
we ask in a special way, Lord, that you
would please speak to your people today.
Lord help us to see clearly to
understand and Lord please minister to
our hearts is our prayer in Jesus name.
Amen.
I want to invite you to the screen. The
title of the sermon is the good
Samaritan.
The good Samaritan.
And we are going to be taking a journey
through a very wellknown parable. The
Bible tells us in the book of Luke 10
25, "Behold, a certain lawyer stood up
and tempted him, saying, Master, what
shall I do to inherit eternal life?"
And he said unto him, "What is written
in the law? How readest thou?"
And he answered and said, "Thou shalt
love the Lord thy God with all thy soul,
and with all thy strength, and with all
thy mind, and thy neighbor as thyself."
I want you to just pause for one moment
and understand here that this lawyer who
is speaking is very familiar with the
law.
Um, I want you to note that he could
have gone anywhere at all in the Old
Testament. He could have mentioned a
number of laws in the Old Testament or
totaling over 600 laws in the Old
Testament, but he narrows in on one
particular law. I want you to listen.
Um, in Deuteronomy chapter 6 verse 5, we
should say two laws, but notice
Deuteronomy chapter 6 verse 5. The Bible
says, "Thou shalt love the Lord thy God
with all thine heart, and with all thy
soul, and with all thy might." And again
in Leviticus 19:18, "Thou shalt not
avenge nor bear any grudge against the
children of thy people, but thou shalt
love thy neighbor as thyself. I am the
Lord."
What I want you to understand here is
that the lawyer who is speaking narrows
in on the correct answer. Jesus, as you
will see, does not correct him and say,
"No, no, no. You've got it wrong." We're
going to see that Jesus literally says
to him, in fact, I'll just go to the
next verse, Luke 10:28. And he said unto
him, "Thou has answered right. This do
and thou shalt live." Verse 29, however,
says, "But he willing to justify himself
said unto Jesus, and who is my
neighbor?" Who is my neighbor? And thus
begins the parable of what we call the
good Samaritan. Let's read this parable
beginning in verse 30.
The Bible says, "And Jesus answered
answering said, a certain man went down
from Jerusalem to Jericho and fell among
the which stripped him of his raignment
and wounded him
and departed,
leaving him half dead."
And by chance
there came down a certain priest that
way. And when he saw him, he passed by
on the other side.
And likewise, a Levite,
a Levite, when he saw at the place, when
he was at the place, I'm sorry, came and
looked on him.
All right.
So, we're going to just switch
microphones here. Can you guys hear me
now?
Just put a one in the chat if you could
hear me
correctly now.
All right, let me go ahead and read Luke
10:30 again. Jesus answered, "A certain
man went down from Jerusalem to Jericho
and fell among these which stripped him
of his reignment and wounded him and
departed, leaving him half dead." And by
chance there came down a certain priest
that way. And when he saw him, he passed
by on the other side. And a Levite, when
he was at the place, came and looked on
him and passed by on the other side.
But a certain Samaritan, as he
journeyed, came where he was. And when
he saw him, he had compassion.
So he went to him and bandaged his
wounds, pouring on oil and wine, and
sent him on his own animal, brought him
to an inn, and took care of him. On the
next day, when he departed, he took out
two denary, and gave them to the
inkeeper, and said to him, "Take care of
him, and whatsoever more you spend, when
I come, I will repay you."
I will repay you.
Verse 36.
All right, everyone. Um, welcome back.
We apologize. This is uh uh we were
having some issues with the microphone,
but again, uh we're going to go ahead
and um pick up where we left off. In
fact, I'm going to go back and read the
parable again. So, uh, let's go back to
the screen. Uh, put a one in the chat if
you can hear me. Uh, should be no
issues.
Uh, yeah. Thank you, tech team. Thank
you, tech team. And let's go to the
screen. Luke 10 verse 25. And behold, a
certain lawyer stood up tempting him,
saying, Master, what shall I do to
inherit eternal life? And he said unto
him, what is written in the law? How
readest thou?
Then he and he answered, saying, Thou
shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy
heart, with all thy soul, and with all
thy strength, and with all thy mind, and
thy neighbor as thyself.
Um, I want you to note here Deuteronomy
10 6 verse uh chapter 6:5. The Bible
tells us that this in fact is one of the
commandments. It says, "Thou shalt love
the Lord thy God with all thine heart,
with all thy soul, and with all thy
might." Please note
that this lawyer is very familiar with
the law. Um, in fact, out of 620 plus
laws that he could have mentioned, he's
he gets right to the very commandment
that Jesus is going to commend him on
it. He understands
that the summary of the law is to love
God with all your heart, all your soul,
all your mind. And then
according to Leviticus 19:18,
the Bible says, "Thou shalt not avenge
nor bear any grudge against the children
of thy people, but thou shalt love thy
neighbor as thyself. I am the Lord." And
I want you to note that these are the
two verses that the the lawyer literally
is quoting from when he answered Jesus's
question. And I want you to take note of
what this lawyer quotes. In fact, go
back to the screen for a minute and I
want you to note something that you may
not have considered before. I'm going to
read it again and I'm not going to point
it out, but I want to read the text
again which says, "Thou shalt not avenge
nor bear any grudge against the children
of thy people, but thou shalt love thy
neighbor as thyself. I am the Lord." I
want you to note something here that
that when the the the text goes on, in
fact, let's go to the next verse. The
Bible says in Luke 10:28, "And he said
unto him,"Thou has answered right, "This
do, and thou shalt live." Jesus is
telling him, you answer the cor the
question correctly. You're right. Out of
600 plus laws, you name the two laws
that I have nothing to add to. You
summarized it well.
The text goes on to say, however, but he
willing to justify himself said unto
Jesus, "And who is my neighbor?" Now,
I want you to understand why
why the the the lawyer goes on to ask
this question.
Why is he trying to justify himself?
What what does the text mean? What is he
trying to say? What is he trying to to
suggest to Jesus? How is he trying to
justify and defend himself?
If you go back to the text, and we're
going to go back again one more time.
Let's go back one more time. We're just
going to go two verses back and let me
read it again.
Thou shalt not avenge nor bear any
grudge against the children of thy
people.
the children of thy people.
The children of thy people, but thou
shalt love thy neighbor as thyself. May
I suggest to you that the lawyer
understands that his neighbor
only means
the children of his people. In other
words, my neighbor is only those that
are like me. My neighbor is only those
who are among
my people.
Keep that thought in your mind as we go
into the parable. In Luke 10:30, Jesus
answered, saying, "A certain man went
down from Jerusalem to Jericho and fell
among thieves, which stripped him of his
raignment and wounded him. and departed,
leaving him half dead. And by chance
there came down a certain priest that
way. And when he saw him, he passed by
on the other side.
And likewise a Levite, when he was at
the place, came and looked on him, and
passed by on the other side. But a
certain Samaritan, as he journeyed, came
where he was. And when he saw him, he
had compassion. So he went to him and
bandaged his wounds, pouring on oil and
wine. and he set him on his own animal
and brought him to an inn and took care
of him. On the next day when he
departed, he took out two dinary, gave
them to the inkeeper and said to him,
"Take care of him, and whatever more you
spend when I come again, I will repay
you." And then Jesus asked the question,
"So which of these three do you think
was neighbor to him who fell among
thieves?" And he said, "He who showed
mercy on him." Then Jesus said to him,
"Go and do likewise." Go and do
likewise. The first thing that I want to
address as we're looking at this parable
is the question
that the lawyer asked. It is a question
that all of us ask. It is a question
that is perhaps the
most important question to everyone who
is seeking
salvation
and the question was this
what shall I do to inherit eternal life?
Now
what I want you to understand here is
that there are many things that are that
are that are described. You know, to
inherit eternal life, we need to do X,
Y, and Z. To inherit eternal life, this
needs to happen. This needs to happen.
This needs to happen. But I want you to
note Jesus's own answer
to the question
when the when the the the the lawyer uh
h says to him um uh love God with all
your heart and love your neighbor as
yourself. There is context to that.
Why is the why is he asking what shall I
do to inherit eternal life? We know that
when man sinned
uh death came into the world. Death came
into the world. In fact, the Bible says
in Romans chapter 6 23, for the wages of
sin is death, but the gift of God is
eternal life through Jesus Christ our
Lord. In John 3:16, for God so loved the
world that he gave his only begotten son
that whosoever believeth in him should
not perish but have everlasting life. So
what the text is telling us here, what
the ver two verses we just read is
telling us is that sin
results in death, but Jesus came into
the world to show us the way to
everlasting life. So there's no better
person to ask than who this lawyer is
asking when he says to Jesus, "What must
we do? What must I do to inherit eternal
life?" And when he answers, listen now.
When he answers, "Love God
and love your neighbor,"
it almost seems to us like a cheap
answer.
like, "Yeah, well, yeah, well, well,
that can't be, you know, just it.
There's got to be something more.
There's got to be something that that's
added on to to this."
But Jesus adds nothing.
He He literally says
to the lawyer, he said unto him,
"Read this for yourself. Thou hast
answered right.
This do
and you shall live.
Now, now let me just pause for a second
and I need to ask you the question.
How many of you in seeing Jesus's own
words where he says if you simply love
God
and love your neighbor you shall live.
Y'all put a one in the chat. Put a one
in the chat if that is good news to you.
Put a one in the chat if you're like,
"Whoa, Jesus just simplified this."
Jesus just said to me, "If I love God
with all that I have and I love my
neighbor as myself,
I will live. I will have eternal life."
Meaning eternal life then is contingent
upon whether we love God
and love our neighbor. It's that simple.
In fact, Romans 13 tells us, "Love
workketh no ill to his neighbor.
Therefore, love is the fulfilling of the
law." Let me read it again. Love
workketh no ill to his neighbor.
Therefore, love is the fulfilling of the
law. That word ill, it means
harmfulness. It means injury. Love works
no injury or no harm to its neighbor.
Has anyone ever fallen ill. Put a one in
the chat. Raise your hand if you have
fallen ill before. May I suggest to you
that when the Bible says here love
workketh no ill to his neighbor
that what it is actually saying is that
sin
if love works no ill to its neighbor
then sin
is illness
and it's illness direct
illness
to his
Adam and Eve.
Is Satan working ill
to Eve?
A yes or no. Put it in the chat. Is
Satan working ill
to Eve.
All right. Can you all see me? Can you
all hear me? I'm not sure you guys
what's going on. If it's the weather,
um,
but you're saying you see me, so all
right, we're good. And you can hear me.
When Satan is tempting Eve, he is
working ill towards her.
When the Bible says as it continues on
uh for God does know in the day you eat
thereof then your eyes shall be open and
you shall be as gods knowing good and
evil. What I want you to see here is
that Satan works ill towards Eve and in
turn makes her ill with sin.
When Eve gives the fruit unto her
husband,
she is working ill towards him and then
he becomes ill with sin. So in other
words,
sin,
if we can say this way, sin
is the disrupting
of a relationship
between two parties.
Sin is is when a relationship between
two parties changes not for the better
but for the worse.
If I can say it this way,
every one of us has a relationship with
with our parents, with our siblings,
with our neighbors, and even with people
that we don't know. A and there is a
proper context for every relationship.
husband and wife, parent and child,
friend and friend, friend and and
neighbor. Uh there are there are go
there are parameters that keep a
relationship safe. So when a when a man
and woman are married, there is a
context to their relationship. But when
the context of their relationship
changes, meaning the woman decides to
have an illicit relationship with
someone else or the man decides to have
an illicit relationship, this is sin.
Sin is when a relationship becomes
illicit. It can happen not only between
husband and wife, but it can happen with
friends. It can happen with people that
you don't know. For example,
if God says to love your neighbor, then
the correct relationship with people who
you know and people who you do not even
know should be love. But when you run
upon a stranger and the stranger does
something that you don't like and you
now get angry with that n with that with
that stranger, you have defiled a
relationship even with someone that you
don't know. And that is what sin is.
Love workketh no ill to his neighbor.
Sin equals sickness.
Sin kills while love heals. That's what
the Bible is trying to tell us. That's
what God is trying to tell us. Sin does
damage while love heals.
So
again, remember what this lawyer says.
He willing to justify himself said unto
his neighbor, said unto Jesus, "And who
is my neighbor?"
You guys, does this question sound
familiar to you? I want you to think
carefully with me.
Does this question, who is my neighbor?
He's talking to Jesus. Who is my
neighbor? Does this question or the
spirit of the question at all sound
familiar to you?
I'm waiting for y'all. I'm waiting to
see this in the chat. I'm waiting to see
if you might be thinking of exactly what
I am thinking of. And if you're not,
let's just go there.
Come with me to the book of Genesis,
chapter 4,
where Adam,
Adam's two sons, Cain
and Abel,
have just had an unfortunate
interaction. Cain has changed his
relationship
to his brother.
He has altered or created an illicit
relationship with his brother. Meaning
where he was to love his brother, he now
hates him. And we know the story. Cain
kills Abel. And when God comes to the
garden look or when God comes to Cain
looking for Abel, Abel or Cain asked the
question, when God says, Cain, where is
Abel, thy brother? He said unto him, I
know not. Am I my brother's keeper?
Who is my neighbor? Am I my brother's
keeper?
You see, am I my brother's keeper?
Was the response of a murderer.
And I want you to see what Jesus is
getting to here, beloved. Because when
this lawyer asks, "And who is my
neighbor?" He is asking it in the same
spirit as Cain.
You see what Jesus is trying to
demonstrate here is that in the parable
it seems obvious that the thief is the
is the
is the murderer. Of course, the man is
not murdered. He's only left for half
dead. But in the parable, you're
thinking, "Oh, the thief is the bad
guy." Why? because he committed an act
of of he was trying to kill the man. He
left him for dead. So we think to
ourselves, the thief is the murderer. By
the way, his relationship with this man,
whoever this man is, is an illicit
relationship. In other words, where this
man should have loved this man, this
thief attempts to kill this man.
In the parable, you're tempted to think,
who's the bad guy? Oh, it's the thief.
The thief is Cain. The thief is a bad
guy. The thief is the one that kills.
And we are not like the thief. But I
need you to understand something. While
the thief was a murderer by commission,
the the the priest and the Levite who
pass by are murderers by omission. Y'all
put a five in the chat. Put a five in
the chat if you are beginning to
understand the heart of this message
today. The thief and the Levite in
passing by on the other side
were murderers not by commission. In
other words, they are not the ones that
actually killed the man. They are
murderers by omission.
They were willing to let the man die.
In this story, the Samaritan is the hero
because a man that he does not know, he
shows a relationship of love and
compassion to him.
Jesus is trying to tell us here in this
parable and he's trying to express to
the lawyer
that your neighbor is any human being
that is in need.
It's not just the children of your own
people. The way he misread Leviticus 19.
Oh, it's just my people. If anyone I
should not oppress my people but other
people. I can oppress other people. I
cannot like other people. Yet those are
not my neighbors. Those are foreigners.
Those are the people that are not like
us.
But what we need to understand, beloved,
is that while the priest and the Levite
did not pull out the gun, did not pull
out the knife, did not pick up the stone
to kill the person, they are in fact
murderers by omission
because they did not extend the love,
the compassion that one would that one
should extend
to the neighbor.
The Samaritan in this story is the hero.
And you can imagine how they could not
stand that because the Samaritan is not
one of us.
And I want you to note now beloved, I
want you to watch this carefully. Okay?
Let's go back to the screen and I want
you to note this.
So the Bible says in Luke 10:33,
"But a Samaritan
as he journeyed came where he was, and
when he saw him, he had compassion on
him and went to him." Now stop right
here. Stop right here.
Everything else you're about to read
from here on from here out is almost
irrelevant.
It's almost irrelevant. what the
Samaritan does is it is not irrelevant,
but for the purpose of what we're what
we're looking at today, it is almost
irrelevant. And here's what I mean when
I say it is almost irrelevant.
The Samaritan
did not
in order to d to try to demonstrate,
hey, I've got love for this man, did not
let me read it. Let me read it. He went
to him, bound up his wounds, pouring in
oil and wine, and set him on his own
beast, and brought him to an end, and
took care of him. Please listen.
This was not done in order for the
Samaritan
to try to develop a love for this
neighbor.
This was done as the outgrowth
of the love and mercy the Samaritan had
on his neighbor.
Do you understand what I just said?
It stops right at compassion. As soon as
we read he had compassion on him,
everything else after that was simply an
evidence of the compassion that the
Samaritan had in his heart,
demonstrating, watch, demonstrating that
in the heart of this Samaritan was the
love of God and the love of neighbor.
It was already there. the Pharisee and
the Levite or the priest and the Levite
walking past the neighbor was not the
walking past the neighbor
was simply the evidence of what was
already in their hearts.
Are y'all understanding what I'm saying?
What was already in the heart was being
played out. Priest and Levite already
murderers. Why? Because they did not
love their neighbor.
And beloved, what I need you to
understand
is that for a lot of us today, we're
becoming very flippant, very flippant in
our and almost boastful
in our lack of care for our neighbors.
And what I need you to understand,
beloved, is that when we ask a question,
well, who is my neighbor? Your neighbor
is not described in the Bible as those
who are born where you were born.
According to Jesus,
the neighbor is that other person, the
one not like you. You understand the
history between the Jews and the
Samaritans.
And so the last thing that they would
expect to hear is that the Samaritans
were their neighbors.
Please understand
that when the Samaritan goes and and and
pours oil and wine and sets him on his
own beast and brings him to the inn and
takes care of him and and and and and
leaves money and says to the host, "Take
care of him and when and whatever you
spend when I come again, I will repay
you." Just know that all of that was the
outflow of what was in the Samaritan's
heart.
Note with me again how the Bible says on
the when he departed, he took out two
pence and gave them to the host and said
unto him, take care of him and
whatsoever you spend more when I come
again, I will repay thee.
When I come again, I will repay thee.
I'm coming back to that statement.
But I need you to understand something.
I need you to catch this here, beloved.
Because you see this word neighbor, the
Greek for the word neighbor is pion. And
it literally means near, to come near.
Meaning then that the neighbor we may
say is the nearer.
The neighbor,
the true neighbor is the one who will
come close to another.
So now you got two groups of people.
Those who pass by and those who come
close. The ones who come close, they are
the true neighbors. They have the spirit
of Christ. The ones who pass by, nah,
stay far away from me and keep them far
away from me and keep them far away from
us. Please understand,
please understand
that those with the spirit of
stay far away from me because I know
you're kind and I know your type, you
Samaritans.
are literally exemplifying
the spirit of the priest and the Levite.
No, no, no, no, no. They are not
murderers by commission and would
probably never be murderers by
commission. But you are murdering by
omission.
Am I my brother's keeper?
Is that my neighbor?
It's the same spirit. It's the same.
It's the same heart.
Beloved, I believe this is why Jesus put
these things in the Bible. Let's go to
Leviticus chapter 9. Leviticus chapter
19:34 where the Bible says, "The
stranger who dwells among you shall be
to you as one born among you, and you
shall love him as yourself, for you were
strangers in a land in the land of
Egypt. I am the Lord your God." In other
words, you were foreigners.
Never forget that you were foreigners in
a land that wasn't your homeland.
Remember how you were treated and do not
treat others the way you were treated.
No, I am the Lord your God. Watch this.
Let's go back to the screen. It's almost
like God is saying, "Here is why I'm
commanding you to do this. I'm
commanding you to treat those who are
strangers as one born among you as
neighbors. I am the Lord your God. It's
almost as if he's saying, "Hold on now.
I need you to understand my character. I
need you to understand who I am. And I
need you to understand that who I am
determines who you are. So because I am
the Lord your God and I want you to be
like the Lord your God. I am commanding
you to love your neighbor. Well, who is
my neighbor? Oh, who is your neighbor?
Your neighbor is the stranger. Your
neighbor is the one that was not born
among you. I'm going somewhere with
this. I want you to follow along. In
Exodus 23:9, also you shall not oppress
a stranger, for you know the heart of a
stranger because you were strangers in
in the land of Egypt. You know what it
was like to be a stranger.
And that's why I'm telling you, do not
oppress the stranger.
Deuteronomy chapter 10 verse 18 and 19,
he administers justice for the
fatherless and the widow and loves the
stranger. Whoa, wait a minute.
God loves the stranger.
You would you would think you would
think by the things we hear today that
God hates the stranger.
That God hates the stranger.
And yet, beloved, this is very far from
the truth. God loves the stranger.
Giving him food. What?
That's our food. That's our clothing.
No, no, no. God loves the stranger.
Giving him food and clothing. Therefore,
because God loves a stranger, I command
you to love the stranger. Now, remember,
remember what Jesus said, right? He said
this, "Do thou shalt live."
And what I need you to understand,
beloved, is that the devil will find a
thousand different ways to get you lost.
He will find a thousand different ways
to get you to exemplify hatred either
for God or for your neighbor. And one of
the easiest ways for him to get you to,
you know, hey, I'm not killing my
neighbor. I'm just saying, who is my
neighbor? I'm just saying, am I my
brother's keeper? It's not even my
brother.
Please understand,
understand
that the enemy of souls is simply trying
to get you to act like that thief, like
that priest, or like that Levite.
If he can't get you to kill by
commission, he will get you to kill by
omission.
And beloved, listen to me. When you kill
by omission, I need you to understand
here in this parable, in this parable,
what I need you to understand is that
Jesus is the man that left heavenly
Jerusalem to come down to this earth.
He was on his way, beloved, to be a
neighbor, to be a nearer to us
because we were in sin. We were in need.
We were sickened
with the sin.
We were sickened with sin. And Jesus in
the parable, watch this you guys, in the
parable, he is the man working his way
down, coming from heaven down to earth.
And when he gets to earth, y'all, he is
jumped by a bunch of thieves.
The Bible says in Isaiah 53:3 and 4, he
is despised and rejected of men, a man
of sorrows and acquainted with grief.
And we hid as it were our faces from
him. We passed by on the other side. We
were the priest. We were the Levite. We
were the thief. Wow. Wow. He was the
spies and we esteemed him not. We passed
by. In fact, you can read in Matthew 27,
Matthew Matthew 27 when Jesus is on the
cross and the Bible literally says, "And
they passed by wagging their heads."
Come on, somebody. He was despised and
we esteem him not. Surely he has borne
our griefs and carried our sorrows. Yet
we did esteem him stricken, smitten of
God. But he was wounded. Y'all see this?
He was wounded for our transgressions.
He was bruised for our iniquities. The
chastisement of our peace was upon him,
and with his stripes we are healed. All
we like like sheep have gone astray and
we have turned everyone his way,
everyone to his own way. And the Lord
laid on him the iniquity of us all.
Y'all listen to me. Watch this y'all.
Not only in this parable is Christ the
man who fell among thieves.
Almost as if the parable is trying to
tell us Jesus is the lamb of God who
came into this world to die for our sins
to be wounded for our transgressions. In
this parable, Jesus is not only the man
who came down from the heavenly
Jerusalem to to to to be a nearer to us.
But in this parable, he is also the good
Samaritan.
Come on y'all. Let me let me read to
you. Malachi 4:2. But unto you that fear
my name shall the son of righteousness
arise with healing in his wings, and you
shall go as go forth as and grow up as
cows in the stall. Please understand
that not only is Jesus in this parable,
the man who was wounded and beaten and
left for dead, but he is also the
Samaritan, the one who came to this
world to pick up our bodies. Our bodies
left for dead. to pick us up who were
bruised and beaten by iniquity and to
heal us.
Jesus is demonstrating in this parable
the love of God for man. And what God
wants to demonstrate is the love of man
for God and for neighbor. In other
words, in this parable, he is both the
lamb and the priest. He is the man left
for dead and he's the good Samaritan.
And Jesus wants us to reflect that. And
watch this. Remember how remember the
last words of the Samaritan. When I come
again, I will repay.
When I come again, I will repay.
Come on, let me break it down for you.
Matthew chapter 25. Matthew chapter 25.
Note the words of the Good Samaritan.
when I come again, I will repay. In
Matthew 25:34, then shall the king say
unto them on his right hand, then shall
the good Samaritan, capital G, capital
S, then shall the king say unto them on
the right hand, come ye blessed of my
father, inherit the kingdom prepared for
you from the foundation of the world.
Why? For I was hungry, and you gave me
meat. I was thirsty and you gave me
drink. I was a stranger and you took me
in. Naked and you clothed me. I was sick
and you visited me. I was in prison and
you came unto me. Then shall the
righteous answer him, saying, Lord, when
saw we thee a hungered and fed thee, or
thirsty, and gave thee drink? Or when
saw we thee a stranger, and took thee to
the inn? When, Lord, did we see you as a
stranger and pick you up off the side of
the road and bring you to the inn?
Took the inn.
To the inn.
When did we see you naked and clothe
thee or sick or in prison and came unto
thee? I don't remember that. I remember
I remember there was this neighbor of
mine
that was beaten and half left for dead.
But that was the neighbor. That wasn't
that wasn't you, was it?
You're not the stranger.
Ah, and then we remember Jesus's last
part of the words, last words in verse
40 when he says, "And the king shall
answer and say unto them, verily I say
unto you, in as much as you have done it
unto the least of these, my brethren,
you have done it unto me, and as Clint
just said in the chat, be careful to
entertain strangers, for some have
thereby unwittingly entertained angels."
Do you know how many people are going to
have to answer
for the way you treated the stranger,
not realizing that you were entertaining
angels.
You see, God wants his people to be good
Samaritans.
And good Samaritans have the oil and the
wine.
You understand that the oil is symbolic
of the Holy Spirit and the wine is
symbolic of the gospel. You understand,
beloved, that the Holy Spirit and the
gospel are what God's people have been
called upon
to go give. Remember what Jesus said.
Remember what Jesus said, go and do
likewise. In other words, he's saying, I
need you to replicate the work of the
good Samaritan. Remember, remember,
let's go back
when Jesus said when Jesus, in fact, I'm
just going to read it. Which thou of
these three thinkst thou was neighbor
unto him that fell among the thieves.
And he said, he that showed mercy on
him, then said Jesus, go and do
likewise. Go and do likewise. I want you
to go and find those who are half dead,
who are left for dead, and bring them to
the end.
Don't pass by.
bring them to the end. Be a nearer. This
is a calling. This is a commission. And
now I want you to understand something.
At the end of time,
this is the group of people that the
devil is angry with. Let me break it
down for you. Revelation 12 verse 17.
The dragon was wroth and with the woman
and went to make war with the remnant of
her seed which keep the commandments of
God and have the testimony of Jesus
Christ. Meaning meaning the dragon is
angry with the good Samaritans.
Let me stop for a second.
The lawyer asks Jesus, "What shall we do
to inherit eternal life?" Jesus points
him to the law. Says, "How do you read
the law?" And the lawyer says, "Love thy
neighbor, love God with all thy heart,
and love thy neighbor as thyself." And
Jesus says, "You got it. You answered
right. You are you got it. You have
answered correctly."
Do you understand what this means,
beloved? Those
who keep the commandments of God are the
good Samaritans.
Which means at the end of time, the
devil is after good Samaritans.
Which means what I need you to
understand is that if you claim to be an
Adventist,
but you don't have the love of God in
your heart for neighbors, you're not
keeping the law.
The dragon isn't after you. He already
has you.
He's not after you. We should not
flatter ourselves that the dragon is
after us when we're not keeping the law.
What is keeping the law? I go to church
every Sabbath.
Hold on. Y'all must be misunderstanding
something. The lawyer in the in the
story went to church every Sabbath.
The lawyer in the story was a Sabbathke
keeper.
But there was a deeper issue inside him.
He had issues
inside his heart.
So then when the Bible tells us in
Revelation 12:17 that the dragon went to
make war with those that keep the
commandments of God, what is it is in
essence saying is that it's going to
make war with those who have compassion
and empathy
for other people,
thus fulfilling the law of God. Yes,
they keep the letter of the law, but it
doesn't stop at the letter. They also
have the spirit of the law.
You'll remember that the woman in
Revelation chapter 17, uh, she she gives
the world a false wine and she doesn't
even have any oil.
So, no spirit, no spirit, and a
counterfeit gospel.
Did y'all catch that? The good Samaritan
has oil and wine. The woman in
Revelation 17 has no oil, no spirit, and
what she gives is a counterfeit wine, a
wine of wrath. Pause for a second.
So, so good Samaritan oil and wine.
Babylon no oil
but wine. But the wine she has is
wrathful wine.
It's a gospel that embides in wrath.
It's a gospel that that celebrates
wrath,
celebrates anger.
celebrates everything that is unlike
Christ.
It's almost as if, watch this now. It's
almost as if this this this counterfeit
church system is both thief,
Levite, and priest in the parable.
Because you remember, you remember that
the thief comes to kill, steal, and
destroy. Jesus said, "I came to give
life and to that they may have life and
have it more abundantly." But the thief,
this this counterfeit system, which is
exactly what Jesus was speaking to in
his day, because in his day, the people
believed that they were following God,
but had a a hate for neighbor. And while
none of them would say, I would kill my
neighbor, by their acts of omission, I
am keeping my love from you. No, no, no,
no, no, no. You're not one of us. They
were murderers by omission.
So, so we have two things happening at
the at the end of time. There is the
wine of wrath that the devil has control
of of of all who embibe in the wine of
wrath. And those are the ones that are
coming to make war with those who keep
the commandments of God. Meaning they
have the oil, the spirit, and the true
wine, which are both designed, listen to
me, to heal the the ill soul.
Because remember, love workketh no ill
to its neighbor. So the purpose of the
wine and the oil is to heal the people
that have been beaten and bruised and
overcome by sin.
Whereas the wine of the wrath is
designed to beat on people who are not
like them, to deny people who are not
like them. I need you to understand the
two different things happening here. And
so now in this context of the good
Samaritan and being Jesus himself and
then him saying go and do likewise
understand that in this context the
final message in Revelation 14:6 is
really end time good Samaritans going
forward into the world. Let me read it.
I saw another angel fly in the midst of
heaven, having the everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the
earth, to every nation, kindred, tongue,
and people, not to their own people.
They are going forward with wine and oil
for everybody.
They're not asking before initiating the
oil and wine, what country are you from?
What are you doing here?
Who did you vote for?
They're not asking these kinds of
questions.
What What kind of How did you end up
like this? Were you hanging out with the
wrong crowd and got and got and your
your friends turned on you? Or are you a
are you a wine bber? How did you end up
here? Because a a respectable man might
not be in this situation. So, is this
something you brought on? No questions.
Watch this, y'all. No questions.
You're in trouble.
Let me help.
I didn't ask what you believe.
I didn't ask what your thoughts on this.
Not ask. No, you are. You are my
neighbor regardless
regardless
of earthly titles and earthly, you know,
uh uh positions. You are my neighbor.
This is God's planet, not mine,
not yours.
I don't own
pro. This is not my property.
This is God's planet.
And so God says, "I put my children on
this planet and I command you to love
one another.
The preaching of the everlasting gospel
in Revelation chapter 14:6 is in essence
good Samaritans going forward seeking
the seeking those that are left for
dead. What do you mean those that are
left for dead? Let me show you. Saying
with a loud voice, "Fear God and give
glory to him for the hour of his
judgment is come and worship him that
made heaven, the earth, the sea, and the
fountains of waters." And there followed
another angel saying, "Babylon is
fallen, is fallen, that great city,
because she made all nations drink of
the wine of the wrath of her
fornication." Please understand this
mystery Babylon
has stolen salvation from millions and
millions of people and they are half
dead without even knowing it. They are
beaten up by the by the by the lies and
false doctrines and teachings of entire
churches. And God says, "Good
Samaritans, I need you to go in,
find these people who are half dead,
stuck in Babylon, and I need you to
bring them to the end. I need you to I
need you to give them oil. I need you to
give them the true gospel. I need you to
give them the true spirit. I need you to
to to show them what truth is. I need
you to bring them to the end.
And when I come back, I got you
beloved. This means that those who
receive the mark of the beast at the end
of time, those who are destroyed at the
end of time
were either murderers by commission
or murderers by omission.
They were the priest, the Levites,
the thief.
In this parable,
they received the mark of the beast.
Those who receive the seal of God, and
you remember what the seal of God is,
right?
The seal of God is the very sign that
God gave to his people to remind them
that they were once strangers in a land
that was not theirs,
in a place where they were foreigners.
And as a result of them remembering
that, that they should never treat the
stranger as they were treated. Those
who receive the seal of God are those
who have this written in their heart.
And by the way, please note, please note
how the three angels messages end.
Revelation 14:12, here is the patience
of the saints. Here are they that keep
the commandments of God and the faith of
Jesus.
Yeah.
Yeah. Listen, we're we're almost done. I
got one more verse and we're going to
wrap this up. Jeremiah 31:33. But this
is the covenant that I will make with
the house of Israel after those days,
say the Lord. I will put my law into
their minds and write it on their
hearts, and I will be their God, and
they shall be my people. Beloved, too
many of us
too many of us are talking about the Ten
Commandments
as
as a strictly
let me say it this way in a way where we
can check. All right. Yep. I don't do
this. I don't do this. I don't do this.
I don't do this. I don't do this. So
therefore, I am keeping the commandments
of God. When Jesus described the
fulfillment of keeping the law of God
and Paul described it, they both used a
very simple word, love. That word is
being mocked by the enemy today. That
word is being mocked even by Christians
today. We don't talk about loving our
neighbor. No, no, no, no, no, no. We
talk about loving the country. We talk
about uh uh uh loving truth.
But the very thing Jesus says, this is
what is going to get you into the
kingdom of heaven. This is what is going
to seal you. And if you think, well,
sealing, sealing and and and and
treating others nice, how does that
work? Let me just wrap it up with Isaiah
58. Isaiah 58:6. Is not this the fast
that I've chosen? Speaking of the
Sabbath, is not this the fast that I've
chosen to loose the bands of wickedness,
to undo the heavy burdens, to let the
oppressed go free, and that you break
every yoke. Is it not to deal thy bread
to the hungry, and that thou bring the
the poor that are cast out to thy house,
good Samaritan? When thou seest the
naked that thou cover him, and you hide
not yourself from your own flesh, then
shall thy light break forth as the
morning, and thine heart, thy health
shall spring forth speedily, and thy
righteousness shall go before thee, and
the glory of the Lord shall be thy
reward.
You guys,
this parable of the good Samaritan,
when you understand it in an end time
context,
lets us know
that the final test, the reason why as
time goes on, the love of many will wax
cold is because the final test of Satan
will be
to attempt to get God's people
to become murderers
by commission or omission.
And he's leading up to that, beloved.
He's giving us little tests now to see
how do you respond to this? How do you
respond to that? Okay, I see you. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Good. And he's train he's
attempting to train
he's attempting to train
God's people to not love in the name of
Jesus.
And how terrifying a thought that so
many of God's professed people are doing
exactly as this lawyer did when they
asked the question, "Who is my neighbor?
When the laws of this earth or the the
the culture of this earth overrides the
law of God, there is danger.
Beloved, may our prayer be,
may our plea be, Lord, help me to truly
love my neighbor.
Not in a worldly context,
but in a godly context in in with the
way Jesus said to do it. Help me to love
my neighbor in that way. And you know
what? I'm not God. No, no, no. I mean,
no need to say that. But I could just
sense the struggle in the heart of so
many of so many of us as we hear this
message. But you don't understand.
You're asking me to love murderers.
Do you understand that Jesus came down,
left heaven to come near to murderers?
To thieves.
While we were yet enemies, Jesus died
for us.
How dare we
place ourselves above any other human
being
because of who they are, where they are
from, or what they have done.
Do you understand that when when we come
to God weeping with tears, Lord, forgive
me, and he forgives us, and then we go
out, then we go out
and see someone that we think is less
than us and we hem them up.
We're not going to offer you
forgiveness. We're not going to offer
you. We hem them up and we beat them up
and we and we walk by and we No, we're
No, no, no, no. Do you understand
that when you do not extend to others
what God has extended to us
that your citizenship in the kingdom of
heaven will be revoked?
There is no
lifetime guaranteed
citizenship in the kingdom of heaven
when you fail to follow the laws of the
kingdom of heaven.
And so many of us are breaking the laws
of the kingdom of heaven
to honor the laws of this world,
thinking
that we will not get our citizenship
revoked.
May the Lord help us
to live according to the laws of the
kingdom of heaven.
that when Jesus comes again,
the repaying that he gives is a good
repay
is a come ye blessed enter into the
kingdom
that I've gone to prepare for you. You
are a citizen of heaven.
If you would like to be a citizen of
heaven, if you are if you you are not a
citizen of he of heaven and you want to
be a citizen of heaven, number one. And
number two, if you found yourself lately
not really acting like a citizen of
heaven and forgetting what the law of
heaven is and that the law of heaven is
greater than the law of this earth or
the law of any nation,
I want you to put that one in the chat
where you're saying today, Lord,
either forgive me for not acting like a
citizen of the kingdom, forgive me for
breaking the law of the kingdom,
the law of love,
And if I'm not a citizen, if you're not
a citizen, you're saying today, Lord, I
want to become a citizen of the kingdom.
Make me today a citizen of the kingdom.
I want you to put that one in the chat
as I close in prayer.
the end of this message, I'm going to
bring up another slide that's going to
show you how if you are interested in
Bible study, if you want to be baptized,
if you want to give your life fully to
Christ and you want to prepare for
baptism, how you can get in contact with
us so that one of our Bible workers will
be will connect with you and begin to
walk you through Bible study. Um,
and that's for those of you who in
putting the one in the chat, you're
saying, "I need to become a a a citizen
of the kingdom of heaven. Show me how to
do show me how to get my citizenship.
And then for those of you who have said
today, Lord, help me to keep my
citizenship and not give it away by
breaking the law of love in heaven. I
want to pray for both of you right now.
So, let's do that. Heavenly Father,
thank you Lord for speaking again
another word of truth. Thank you for the
fresh mana from heaven to show us, Lord,
especially in the time that we're living
in for us not to get caught up
in any law that requires us to go
against the law of the kingdom of
heaven.
Lord, may we be willing to give up
everything
rather than break the law of heaven.
May we esteem the law of that of that
world greater than the laws of this
world.
And Lord, for those who are praying
today to become citizens of the kingdom
of heaven, I pray that you would lead
them and guide them and that you would
put the fire in their heart. Lord, that
you would grant them a brand new heart
that loves God and loves neighbor
with everything that they have.
Lord, forgive us who have known better.
Forgive us
for exempl or for um
for showing the spirit of the priest,
the Levite, and in some cases even the
thief.
Please Lord, set us right with you.
Grant us the heart of the Samaritan.
Grant us the heart
of you who came down from heaven, down
from the new Jerus, down from Jerusalem,
the heavenly Jerusalem to come to this
earth to draw near to us while we were
yet sinners.
Grant us that heart, Lord. Forgive us
our sins and draw us to you is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen. And amen.
We're going to go ahead and put this
last slide on the screen for you to see.
We're also going to put in the link uh
in the chat uh the link for our
afterglow. I want to thank you guys for
being able uh thank first the tech team
for getting us back up uh despite uh the
the um
uh the link um going dead a couple of
times the microphone. But thank you guys
for jumping back on and for watching
this through. Uh it will be uploaded and
perhaps edited so that we don't have
that whole part at the beginning. But
may God bless you. Um look forward to
connecting with you on alter not on
alter live on the on the afterlow in the
zoom link. And uh again may God bless
you and keep you until we meet again.
And by the way, please remember this
Sunday night I will be addressing I'm
sorry. I am so sorry. There is no
afterglow today. So my apologies on
that. I'm so used to saying the
afterglow, but there is no afterglow
today. So it's after go. It's after go.
So go out there and do the work of the
Lord. Um, I do want to remind you that
this uh Sunday, so that is tomorrow, we
will be uh at 7 PM uh Central Standard
Time, we're going to be doing the 10
horns study part two. Um the why behind
the Sunday law. So, please make sure you
join us then. And again, may God bless
you and keep you. And um we'll see you
tomorrow and next week. God bless.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.